## Ryan Britt

E: britt.ryant@qmail.com | C: (908) 403-1694 | Kill Devil Hills, NC

## **SUMMARY STATEMENT**

Owner/Operator/Captain with naval architecture, marine engineering, and web development expertise. Diverse experience in a leadership role as both an Owner/Operator of a charter boat business and as an engineer. Exploring engineering and tech positions where I can leverage a unique combination of creativity, technical ability, and interpersonal skills.

## **EXPERIENCE**

GalaxE.Solutions; Somerset, NJ - Remote

July2022-Present

Outsource to America Trainee

- Built applications using React, Redux, Express, NodeJS, .NET, SQL, PostgreSQL
- Finished training on AWS Cloud Services such as S3, Lambda, EC2, AWS-Cloud Trial and Cloud Watch
- Worked on a client project that was built with React, Redux, AWS, and PostgreSQL

Griffin Marine; Wanchese, NC

March 2022-July 2022

CAD Designer/Electrical Installer

- Created and maintained detailed CAD drawings for vessels in progress
- Performed vessel installations and improvements including mechanical, and electrical

Jenny Lee Sportfishing; Manasquan, NJ

July 2018-November 2021

Captain/Owner/Operator

- Built and grew an existing small business into a business of a much larger scale both in size of clientele and recognition/internet presence
- Captained an offshore charter/commercial vessel year-round in both Manasquan, NJ and Wanchese, NC
- Performed vessel maintenance and improvements including mechanical, structural, and electrical work
- Managed various employees both on and off the vessel

General Assembly; New York, NY

January 2018-April 2018

Web Development Immersive Student

Canyon Runner Sport Fishing/Freelance Fisherman; Point Pleasant, NJ Captain/1st Mate

March 2016-January 2018

- Shared captain duties. Primarily responsible for all fishing gear, client activities and routine maintenance
- Manage and train junior employees both on-deck and through conducting seminars

Gibbs and Cox; Arlington, VA

August 2014-March 2016

Naval Architect

Internships

- Refined ship superstructure designs using 3D modeling software including Solidworks, AutoCad and Rhino
- Developed ship general arrangements including floor plans, equipment specs, and egress/escape routing
- Assumed role as lead engineer for developing interior volume estimates utilizing GHS software

Undergraduate Research Assistant; Stevens Institute of Technology

Led and aided in research projects for the Davidson Laboratories at Stevens

Jersey Cape Yachts; Lower Bank, NJ

January 2012-August 2013

Naval Engineering Intern; Builder of Custom Sport Fishing Yachts and Full-Service Boatyard

## **EDUCATION/QUALIFICATIONS**

PHP, Laravel, GitHub

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Naval Architecture & Marine Engineering Deans List, Edwin A. Stevens Scholarship, American Bureau of Shipping Scholarship May 2014

General Assembly
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express.Js, React.js, React.Redux, React Native, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL,

United States Coast Guard OUPV license

May 2016